Guide to the M. H. Abrams papers, 1912-2015.
Abrams, M. H. papers
- Series I. Class Materials
  - Subseries I i. English 313: 18th century Literature
    - 18th Century Literature miscellaneous, 1947-1960 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - I. Introduction, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - II. Neo-Classicism, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - III. Neo-Classic Criticism, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - IV. The Language of Neo-Classic Poetry, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - V. Neo-Classic Theory of the Language, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Va. Dryden's Odes, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - VI-VII. Art of the Heroic Couplet, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - VIII. Social and Political Background, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    - IX. Literature and Audience: Pope, Addison, Defoe, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - X-XII. The Rape of the Lock, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - XIII. Basic Themes: Uniformitarianism, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - XIV. Deism and Natural Religion, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - XV-XVI. The Great Chain of Being and Optimism, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - XVII. The Psychology of Ethics: Self Love and Social, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - XVIII-XIX. Humanitarianism and Sentimentalism, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - XIX-XXIV. The Art of Satire (Pope, Dryden, Swift), 1947 (Box 2, Folder 82)
    - Methodism and the Religious Revival, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - The Poetry of Night and of Tombs, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - XXV. Pastoral and Descriptive Poetry: Thomson, etc., 1947 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Subseries I j. English 314: 18th Century Poetry and Prose
    - Three lectures on 18th century music, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - I. Johnson and the Neo-Classic Tradition, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - II-III. Johnson as Poet, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - IV. Boswell and the Art of Biography, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - V. Johnson's Rasselas, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - VI. Oliver Goldsmith, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - VII. Rasselas and Candide, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - VIII. Revolution of 1740s Primitivism and the Return to Nature, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - IX. Warton's Enthusiast and the New Poetry, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - X. William Collins: the allegorization of general propositions, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - XI-XII. Thomas Gray, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - XIII. Tides of Taste in mid-18th century, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - XIV. Gardening and Landscape painting; XV. Tourists, Gothic Architecture, Poetry and the other Arts, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 98)
    - XVI. The Medieval Revival, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 99)
    - XVII. Ossian, Werther, and Wertherism, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 100)
    - XVIII. Rural Poetry: The Deserted Village; XIX. Cotter's Saturday Night, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 101)
    - XX. Realism and Ruralism: George Crabbe, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 102)
    - XXI-XXII. William Cowper, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 103)
    - XXIII. Paine and the American Revolution, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 104)
    - XXIV. Edmund Burke, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 105)
    - XXV. The 18th century Lyric. XXVI, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 106)
    - XXVII. Burns: Songs and Epistles; XXVIII. Satires, Cantata, Narrative Poetry, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 107)
    - XXIX-XXXI. Blake, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Subseries I k. English 417/418/438: Masterworks of the Romantic Period
    - English 418: Romantic Masterworks miscellaneous, 1954-1971 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - English 438: Masterworks of the Romantic Period, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - English 438: Masterworks of the Romantic Period, introduction and prelude, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - English 438: Masterworks of the Romantic Period, introduction and prelude, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - English 417: Romantic Masterworks, Wordsworth's Prelude, 1964-1965 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Wordsworth and the Apocalyptic Tradition (use with 2nd lecture on Prelude), undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - English 438: Blake, "The Four Zoas", 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - English 417/418: Blake, "Book of Thel", "The Four Zoas", undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - English 438: Shelley, "Prometheus Unbound", 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - English 418: Shelley, "Prometheus Unbound", undated (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - English 438: Keats, "The Fall of Hyperion", 1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - English 418: Byron, "Don Juan", undated (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - English 418: Wordsworth "The Prelude", reading notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - English 418: Byron, "Don Juan", undated (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - English 418: Shelley, "Prometheus Unbound", reading notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 30)
    - English 418: Blake, reading notes, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
    - English 418: Bronte, "Wuthering Heights", undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - English 418: Keats, "Odes", undated (Box 5, Folder 33)
    - English 418: Carlyle, "Sartor Resartus", undated (Box 5, Folder 34)
    - English 418: Bronte, "Wuthering Heights", undated (Box 5, Folder 35)
- Series II. Lectures
  - Abstracts: 18th and 19th century essays, undated (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Indiana: Natural Supernaturalism I. The Design of Romantic Poetry, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - Indiana: Natural Supernaturalism II. The Prelude and Autobiography of Crisis, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Indiana: Natural Supernaturalism II. The Prelude and Autobiography of Crisis, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 95)
  - Indiana: Natural Supernaturalism III. The Circuitous Journey, 1963, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 96)
  - Indiana: Natural Supernaturalism III. Alienation and Reconciliation, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  - "A Reply" Abrams Symposium, 1978-1979 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - AAAS: "Art As Such: The Sociology of Modern Aesthetic", 1984-1985, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - "Art As Such: The Sociology of an Aesthetic Theory" drafts and correspondence, circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - AAAS: "Art As Such: The Sociology of Modern Aesthetic", 1984-1997 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Japan: "The Ancient Mariner" Japan lecture, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Kendal: "Three Poems by Coleridge", 2000 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Council of Scholars, Library of Congress: "Literary Criticism: Some New Directions", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - AAAS: "Literary Criticism: Some Institutional Conditions of Innovation", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Clark Library, "From Addison to Kant: Aesthetic Theory and the Exemplary Art", 1980 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - AAAS: "Reply to Ernst Gombrich" correspondence and final copy for printing, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Cornell symposium: "The Philosophy of Literary Criticism", May 1974 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Symposium on the Jefferson Lecture, Library of Congress: "The Apocalyptic Tradition in America", May 5, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - University of Tulsa: "Apocalypse and Mysticism", February 24, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - PMLA: "On Teaching Metrics", 1986 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Council of Scholars, Library of Congress: "Literary Criticism Today: New Directions" correspondence, drafts and references, May 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Blake's Radical Ambiguity" drafts and slides, 1974, 1975, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - "The Radical Ambiguity of Blake's Apocalyptic vision" slides, drafts, transparencies, and note cards, Spring 1974 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - "Augustine's Confession", 1982 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - "Blake's Radical Ambiguity" reading notes and xeroxes, undated (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - University Center for Rational Alternatives: "Humanism and the Humanities" for printing, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - University of Warwick: Wittgenstein and Literary Criticism, opening statement, MS for printing, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - University of Warwick Symposium: Wittgenstein and Literary Criticism notes, April 1974 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - "Comments on Murray Krieger 'A Walking Dream'", May 1981 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Columbia lecture version: "How to Do Things with Texts", 1978 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - NE-SECS, Syracuse: "The Mirror and the Lamp and 18th century Studies", 1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Faculty Meeting: "On Scott Elledge", May 16, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Intro for James McConkey, February 22, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Memorial for Francis Mineka, November 2, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Memorial for Arthur Mizener, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Memorial for Max Black, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Memorial for Eric Blackall, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Memorial for John Benedict, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Memorial for Tony Capeeti, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Memorial for Ephim Fogel, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Memorials for Peter Kahn and Scott Elledge, 1997, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Memorial for Robert R. Wilson, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Memorial for David Daiches, 2005 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Parrishfest, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Introduction for Frank Kermode, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Introduction for Archie Ammons, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Introduction for Helen Vendler, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Robert Pinksy visit and introduction, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Wheaton College: Commentary on Gerald Brown 'Between Philosophy and Literature', 1986 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - MLA session on Prosody, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - University of Washington: Revelation and Revolution in Wordsworth, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - "Coleridge, Baudelaire, and Modernist Poetics" reading notes, undated (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - "What's the Use of Theorizing about Literature" lecture, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Memorial for John Weld, undated (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Phi Beta Kappa: Conversions- The Bible to the Beats, May 1964 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Alexander lectures: I. Idea Design in Romantic Poetry, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Alexander lectures: I. Indiana version (shortened), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Alexander lectures: II. Indiana version (shortened), 1964 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Lecture II: Carbon copy, Natural Supernatural, undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Alexander lectures: II. Wordsworth’s prelude and the Autobiography of Crisis, undated (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Alexander lectures: III. Indiana Version, undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Alexander lectures: III. Alienation and Reconciliation, undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Alexander lectures: IV. The Romantic Epiphany (Indiana), undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Alexander lectures: IV. Indiana version (shortened), undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Alexander lectures: IV. The Romantic Epiphany, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Lecture II. Wordsworth’s Prelude and the Autobiography, undated (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lecture IV. The Romantic Epiphany, undated (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lecture IV. The Circuitous Journey, undated (Box 5, Folder 13-15)
  - Carleton College: "The Life we Live", 2003 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Graduate talk, reading "To Autumn", 2006 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - University of Rochester: "The Habit of Scholarship", 1998 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Cornell trustees: "Amity in Opposition", 2006 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Talk at Kendal: "Poetry in its Variety", 2002 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Ammon's, "Balsam Firs", 2003 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Talks to grad students, "English at Cornell", 2004 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Poetry after the Theory Wars, 2003 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - "An Unlikely Story: The Joyce Collection at Cornell", 2005 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - "The Founding of the National Humanities Center" to be read, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Topics for public lectures, undated, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Ideas for graduate seminars, 1974-1975 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Syracuse, session on "The Mirror and the Lamp", October 7, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - University of Georgia, American Conference on Romanticism, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Keats Bicentennial Conference opening statement, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - PMLA Symposium: "Limits of Pluralism", undated (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - Kendal Symposium: "Where is Science Going?", 1997 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Santa Barbara Conference: "Re-Presenting the Past", undated (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - MLA: "Modes of Romantic Autobiography: A Response", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Talk: "Fundamentalism", 1988; November 20, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Review: GL Hagberg, "Meaning and Interpretation", 1994 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - "The Deconstructive Angel", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Introduction: "Revolutionary Romanticism", 1990 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Brockport: "Reply to More Peckham's 'Romanticism and Behavior'", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Introduction: Symposium on "Time", 1987 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Library of Congress: "Scholarship Today", 1986 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Trilling Seminar: "Comment on Frank Kermode, 'To Keep the Road Open'", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Cornell Colloquium: "Issues in the Humanities", December 6, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - "English Studies: 1930-1990", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - MLA: "Does Romanticism Exist?", 1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - MLA: "English Studies: During my career as student at the MLA", 1994-1997 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Cornell: "What is a Humanistic Criticism?", 1993 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Afterward: "The Site of a Humanistic Criticism", 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Memorial for Eric Blackall, 1990 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - "How Romantic are Wordsworth's 'Lyric Ballad'?", undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - "The Productive Conflict of Opposites", 1954 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Cornell grad students: "Philosophical Metaphors" (Poet: Creator Analogue, 1949 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - University of Michigan: "The Poet as Creator", 1951 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - "The Song of Songs", 1953 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Cornell Wordsworth Symposium: "Wordsworth Today", 1950 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - University of Nebraska: "Wordsworth's Natural Supernaturalism", 1954 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Fraternity: "The Founding of Cornell", 1962 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Dean's List Freshmen: "The Cultural Milieu of Cornell", 1962 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Western Reserve: "The Teaching of Poetry", undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Book and Bowl: "Symbolism of the Title" etc, 1954, 1956, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Book and Bowl: "The Strip-tease as Literary Motif", 1952 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Browning Room, Book and Bowl: "The Recorder", 1956, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Emotive language discussion, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - University of Nebraska: "The New Criticism", 1954 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Library staff: "Literary History", 1956 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Radio Talk: "Common Studies at the Arts College", 1955 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Alumni Talk: "The Great Problems: A Program for Investigation", 1965 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Talk to Track Banquet: Cornell-Penn and Cambridge-Oxford, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Dedication of Uris Library Reading Room, September 21, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - To graduate students: "Making of The Mirror and the Lamp", 1961, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Round Table: "The Significance of Wordsworth Today", 1950 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Vicious Circle: "Alienation and Reconciliation", 1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in Behavioural Sciences: "Alienation: The Ancient History of a Modern Idea", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "From Wordsworth to Proust: Idea and Design in Portraits of the Artist", 1969 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - "The Poet's Vision: Romantic and Post Romantic", 1966, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - The College English Association: "Freshness of Sensation: Romantic and Post Romantic", 1966 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Vicious Circle: "The Secret of Hegel's Phenomenology, 1968 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Yale, Hopkins: "Wordsworth's Prelude and Hegel's Phenomenology, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Thoughts for a talk: "The One Culture", undated (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - "Campus Planning", 1966 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Toward a talk on "Scholarly Publishing", undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - American Philosophical Society: "Coleridge's Light in Sound", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Long Branch, NJ, High School Hall of Fame, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "A Program for Cornell", 1958 (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Arts College Council, The Society of Fellows at Cornell, 1959 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - American Philosophical Society: Coleridge notes, undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - "What is a Humanistic Criticism?" lecture version, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Yale: "The Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2009 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - "How to Prove an Interpretation" lecture version, 1976-1981 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - "How to Prove an Interpretation" lecture notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - "How to Prove an Interpretation" lecture notes, 1976, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Talk at football reunion, 2008 (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2006-2007 (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Morgan Library: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2008 (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Morgan Library: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2008 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Harvard: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2007 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Cornell: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2008 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - NHC: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2007 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Cornell: "On Reading Poems Aloud", 2007 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - "On Reading Poems Aloud" notes, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Cornell: "This Green World: The Vision of Nature in the Romantic Poets", 1999 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - NHC: "This Green Earth: The Vision of Nature in the Romantic Poets", 2000 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
  - "This Green Earth: The Vision of Nature in the Romantic Poets" outlines and notes, 2011 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - "This Green Earth: The Vision of Nature in the Romantic Poets" for revision, undated (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University: "Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2010 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Cornell Alumni: "Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2009 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Cornell: "Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2010-2011 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Cornell: "Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2012 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - "Reading Hopkins Aloud, undated (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Kendal: "John Keats and A.R. Ammons: Poems on Life and Time", 2005 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Yale: "Fourth Dimension of a Poem", 2009 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Cornell: "An Unlikely Story: The Joyce Collection at Cornell", includes miscellaneous documents, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Guerlac Seminar: "Literature and Science", 1950 (Box 17, Folder 22)
  - Notes "English Literature", 1952 (Box 17, Folder 23)
  - Subseries IIa. Outside Lecture Correspondence and Invitations
    - Rice, Vassar, Texas, Haverford, Stanford, LeMoyne, 1964-1965 (Box 8, Folder 33)
    - St. Lawrence, Penn State, Vanderbilt, Bucknell, 1965-1967 (Box 8, Folder 34)
    - Arizona, SUNY Albany, Irvine, AAAS- La Jolla, 1967-1968 (Box 8, Folder 35)
    - Albany, Notre Dame (refusal), Harvard, Yale, 1968-1969 (Box 8, Folder 36)
    - Johns Hopkins, Canisius, California State College, Stony Brook, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 37)
    - University of Nevada, Ohio State, 1970-1971 (Box 8, Folder 38)
    - Association for Asian Studies, Hartwick college, Columbia University, 1971-1972 (Box 8, Folder 39)
    - University of British Columbia, Princeton, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 40)
    - Cambridge, Connecticut, American Academy, American Philosophical Society, Georgia, 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 41)
    - University Center for rational Alternative, Maryland, Binghamton, University of Toronto, Warwick, Kenyon, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 42)
    - Berkeley, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - University of Warwick, Brockport, 5toronto, Cornell Lit. Club, Columbia, Manhattanville, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Montana, Buffalo, Chicago, Irvine, Minnesota, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Virginia, UCLA, New Mexico, Santa Barbara, CalTech, USC, 1975-1976 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Dalhousie, McMasters, Drew, Rochester, Duke, Miami, Binghamton, Leicester, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Society for Value Inquiry, Carleton, Columbia, Wisconsin, Rochester, Society for 18th Century Studies, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - University of Indiana, Kent State, Northern Illinois, Brown, MIT, Dartmouth, Temple, 1978 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - Augusta, Northwestern, Louisiana, Texas, Iowa, South Carolina, Virginia, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Dickson, Georgetown, LSU, Williams, National Humanities Center, Cincinnati, Pittsburgh, Rice, Houston, North Western, Brigham Young, Notre Dame, 1979-1981 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Houston, Vancouver, Northwestern, Bob Benner Associates, Academy of Arts and Sciences, Daedalus, Irvine, Columbia, British Columbia, UCLA, Virginia, Purdue, Queens, Alfred, Indiana, Catholic University, Portland State, Kenyon, 1980-1981 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - American Society for Aesthetics, Missouri-Columbia, Chicago, Fordham, St. Louis, Miami, Illinois at Urbana, Yale, Binghamton, MIT, 1981 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - New Mexico, Iowa, Michigan, Cleveland, UNC, Virginia, NHC, Catholic, 1982-1983 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Renascence, Vanderbilt, Colorado, Williams College, Calgary, Kenyon, Rochester, UVA, 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Charleston, Chicago, University of Haifa, Mississippi, Academy of Arts and Science, 1984-1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Lawrence, Notre Dame, Chapel Hill, 1985-1986 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - College de France, MLA, Temple, Keats-Shelley Association, Wheaton, Notre Dame, Western Maryland, Loyola, Tulsa, North Carolina, Rutgers, 1986-1987 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Providence, Brigham Young, Schweitzer Program, Naval Academy, Akron, NYPL, Yale, Indiana, Johns Hopkins, English Literary Society of Japan, 1987-1988 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Ohio State, Edinburgh, Providence, Kentucky, Transylvania University, Rochester, 1989-1989 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Santa Barbara, Bucknell, 1989-1990 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - St. Olaf College, Edinburgh, Baldwin-Wallace, SUNY Geneseo, Hamilton, 1990-1991 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Indiana, Nevada, Alabama, Le Moyne, Marquette, 1991-1993 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Kenyon, St. Olaf, National Humanities Center, Long Branch Public School, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - China and Taiwan, 1985-1990 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - NYU, Kenyon, Union, 1994-1995 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - All Souls College, 1977 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Columbia, Johns Hopkins, Stanford, Princeton, 1959 (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Series III. Correspondence
  - General correspondence, September 1950-August 1953 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - General correspondence, September 1954-August 1955 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - General correspondence, September 1955-August 1956 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - General correspondence, September 1956-August 1957 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Committee for the Society of Fellows in the Humanities correspondence and notes, 1958-1976 (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Edition of Biographia Literaria correspondence and notes, 1957-1975 (Box 8, Folder 30-31)
  - General correspondence, September 1960-August 1961 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - General correspondence, September 1961-August 1962 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - General correspondence, September 1962-August 1963 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Cardinal Newman Portrait, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - General correspondence, September 1963-August 1964 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General correspondence, September 1964-August 1965 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - General correspondence, September 1965-August 1966 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General correspondence, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - General correspondence, September 1967-August 1968 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - University of Pennsylvania appointment, 1968 (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - General correspondence, September 1969-August 1970 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - General correspondence, September 1970-August 1971 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - General correspondence, September 1971-August 1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - General correspondence, September 1972-August 1973 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - General correspondence, September 1973-August 1974 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - General correspondence, 1974-1975 (Box 9, Folder 34)
  - General correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 9, Folder 35)
  - General correspondence, 1976-1978 (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - General correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 9, Folder 37)
  - General correspondence, 1978-1982 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - General correspondence, 1982-1991 (Box 10, Folder 19)